

# **Akshat Gupta**

### Technical Manager

My journey includes exploring the world of tech from a technical, marketing and managerial perspective. With over 3 years of industry experience in Software Development, I have led and managed teams consisting of more than 30 people globally. A well-rounded business mindset with a technical touch helps me make reasonable decisions and stand out amongst my peers.

akshatvg23@gmail.com

Chennai, India

n linkedin.com/in/akshatvg

github.com/akshatvg

M akshatvg.medium.com

+91 8799979997

www.akshatvg.com

twitter.com/akshatvg

stackoverflow.com/users/11494538/akshat-gupta

SEO/SEM

(O) instagram.com/akshatvg

### **EDUCATION**

## University

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore

06/2018 - Present

Information Technology

## **High School**

Chinmaya Vidyalaya, Taylors Road

06/2004 - 06/2018

PCMC

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Web Development Cloud Computing

Digital Marketing Management WordPress

### MANAGERIAL SKILLS

Public Speaking Leadership Teamwork Operations

Finance Management Adaptability Strategising

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Operations and Project Manager**

LegalForce RAPC Worldwide

07/2021 - Present

Tasks:

Working as an all-rounded manager for two ventures under the firm- Trademarkia and Nearcast, I was able to balance both corporate and startup work-styles as Trademarkia is an established company running from more than 12 years whereas Nearcast is a startup we had to bring up from scratch.

I helped them create their own in-house engineering teams as the tech team was outsourced before. This included understanding business logic, the tech stack used and hire a team to maintain legacy code and relaying the same to new developers who parallelly revamped the applications into modern tech stacks.

I also helped set up the engineering office in Chennai and handled the finances and operations for the Indian entity.

Setting deadlines, tracking progress, motivating developers & designers, striving towards a product-market fit and coordinating with VCs and Advisors is something I did on a daily basis.

Whenever there was a deadline, I did not hesitate to contribute to the Flutter app and React web teams. I ensured code quality was upto production standards.

Contact: Raj Abhyanker - +1 (408) 398-3126

## Developer Evangelist Intern

### <u>Agora</u>

07/2020 - 11/2021

Tasks:

I started my journey with Agora by winning a hackathon sponsored by Agora. I started exploring the Agora SDKs and joined the Superstars program. I continued as a member of the program for over a year and mastered the Web SDKs for both RTC and RTM. I was then promoted to the role of a Developer Evangelist Intern in January 2021 under the DevRel team.

In this journey, I was able to help thousands of developers by making Open-Source projects demo-ing how the Web SDK works and how the most daunting tasks could be solved with few lines of code.

Along with a colleague, I conducted workshops teaching Web Development in universities like Columbia, Penn State, NYU, Harvard, UCSC and CalTech, helping participants learn how they could make a functional video calling websites.

I managed the web support channels on Slack as well as Stack Overflow to ensure developers could utilise the fullest potential of the Agora SDKs.

Lastly, I also wrote technical blogs to serve as guides for priority features and examples which would be helpful to developers.

Contact: William Du - +1 (443) 345-6242

### **PROJECTS**

### Translated Transcription Service (10/2021)

 Web application to create translated transcribed text to and from any language during video calls using the Agora Web SDKs.

### Common Entry Test (12/2020 - 01/2021)

- One stop solution to make club and chapter recruitments in VIT simpler and hassle free.
- This project was used by over 17 clubs, teams and chapters in 2020 with over 70,000 page views and 3,000+ unique users.

### Digital Beti (02/2020 - 12/2020)

 Web portal for DigitalBeti, a joint initiative by Facebook and the Government of India to overcome the digital gender gap in India by training women from rural areas to become entrepreneurs, using digital tools.

### Josh Skills (06/2020 - 07/2020)

• Mobile first website for Josh Skills with an aim to improve the brand's SEO & online presence for their online courses.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

### First Place (Profitech 2021) (08/2021)

Won the First Place in the Technology Track out of 240 registered global users.

### Second Place (DEVSPACE 2021) (03/2021)

Won the Second Place in the Industrial Collaborations by Dyte track out of 1,414 registered users.

#### Third Place (WomenTechies 2021) (03/2021)

Won the Second Runner Up award in this women-centric hackathon out of around 380 registered users.

#### First Place (VIT Hack 2020) (10/2020)

Won the first place in the Gravitas AI Case partner problem statement as well as the AWS Educate open challenge out of over 1,200 registered participants.

# Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award (09/2020)

Awarded the Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award for exemplary performance at various National & International events and in recognition of my academic performance.

#### Audience's Favourite (RTE Hack 2020) (09/2020)

Won the Audience's Favourite Award by being the top voted and most liked project of the hackathon.

# Best Healthcare Hack (Hophacks Fall 2019) (09/2019)

Won the best Healthcare Hack award powered by Siemens Healthineers out of 44 submitted projects.

### LANGUAGES

#### **English**

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

#### Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

#### Tamil

Limited Working Proficiency

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# Google Cloud Platform Business Professional Accreditation (11/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: 63280081

# Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure (05/2019 - Present)

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

# Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: LGT29UQ8TT8L

# Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: 7GRE2XB43TCG

# Elastic Google Cloud Infrastructure: Scaling and Automation (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: WSEU3OHHJPCW

# Reliable Google Cloud Infrastructure: Design and Process (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: 4G3PTX7RJVCS

# The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing (07/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

## Google Analytics for Beginners

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

### **Advanced Google Analytics**

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

### **Google Analytics for Power Users**

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

### Getting Started With Google Analytics 360

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

### Introduction to Data Studio

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

### Google Tag Manager Fundamentals

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

### Python (Basic) (09/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: B7D22892D983